# Samuel Damashek

6315 Tisbury Dr, Burke, VA 22015

#### **Contact**

Cell: 571-358-2032

e-mail: samuel.damashek@gmail.com

#### **Profile**

I am a highly driven high-school student at the Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology interested in a career in computer security. My self-taught skills in computer programming and Linux systems administration have been honed through real-world experience in internships and volunteer activities.

# **Key Skills**

Proficient with:

- Linux systems administration and security concepts
- Virtualization concepts and products, including KVM, Libvirt, QEMU, and XenServer.
- Python and C programming languages
- Django and Flask Python web frameworks
- Deployment and management of Apache and Nginx webservers
- · Common networking structures and concepts
- Network management using Cisco IOS, HP Procurve, and Juniper Junos switches

# Familiarity with:

- Web languages (HTML/CSS/JS) and Java.
- Common cryptographic standards (RSA, AES, MD5/SHA1/SHA2, ECDHE) and implementations (GnuPG, SSL).

#### **Education**

**2013 to 2017** Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology, Alexandria, VA

# **Work Experience**

### Invincea Labs, LLC

June 2015 - present

Research Intern, Computer Network Operations

- Developed an Intrusion Prevention System fingerprint tool using Python and Scapy
  - Researched rule processing differences between different Intrusion Prevention Systems, including Snort and Suricata, and reported on findings
- Assisted with implementation of long-term infrastructure projects
  - Helped roll out OpenLDAP directory for user management and authentication
- Developed a tool to parse and generate payloads from Peach fuzzer Pit files using Python

# Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology

**September 2013 - present** 

Co-lead of Infrastructure, Student Systems Administrator Program (unpaid) September 2014 - present

- Manages student user accounts using Kerberos for authentication and OpenLDAP for directory storage
- Administers KVM virtualization using Libvirt management
- Administers Cisco IOS, HP Procurve, and Juniper Junos switches
- Helped deploy Salt configuration management system on school servers
- Coded a root password management system using Python and PGP/GnuPG
- Developed and assisted in the implementation of a school-wide SSL certificate authority
- Assisted with the installation and configuration of a high performance computing cluster

# **Binary Group**

May 2012 - September 2012

Volunteer Intern

 Assisted with the design, development, and testing of a mobile application developed to help caseworkers coordinate care for homeless veterans

# **Professional Activities and Achievements**

# **Awards**

- First place (team), MITRE STEM CTF 2015 College Division
- Ninth place (team), DEFCON 23 CTF Finals (2015)
- Qualified for and attended CODEGATE 2015 Junior CTF finals in Seoul, South Korea (individually)
- First place (team), Metropolis Cyber Skyline at University of Maryland (2015)
- Sixth place (team), PicoCTF 2014 by Carnegie Mellon University
- First place (team), MITRE STEM CTF 2014 College Division
- Volunteer Gold Star Award from Fairfax County Department of Neighborhood and Community Services (2014)
- First place (team), Booz Allen Hamilton Data Science Bowl (2013)
- First place (team), MITRE STEM CTF 2013